<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Writing on Elise Cutts</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/categories/science-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Writing on Elise Cutts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Elise Cutts</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elisecutts.com/categories/science-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some of my newbie science writing mistakes</title>
      <link>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-10-21-newbie-science-writer-edits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-10-21-newbie-science-writer-edits/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit over three months now since I started writing
1. Forgetting to consider conflicts of interest     The single most important decision I made related to science writing was joining NASW. For students, it&amp;rsquo;s only $20 to join and the value is fantastic. NASW offers networking opportunities, hosts an annual conference for science writers, and has lots of resources, fellowships, and other support for science writers at every stage of their careers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got my first science journalism clip</title>
      <link>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-07-17-my-path-to-a-first-science-news-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-07-17-my-path-to-a-first-science-news-story/</guid>
      <description>I suspect that there are plenty of other researchers out there who are at least toying with the idea that writing about science might be more fun than actually doing it. But how to start?
Breaking into science writing without media experience is intimidating, but it is possible. My first reported science story ran this week in Science News, and seeing as the obligatory rounds of self-promotional texts have been sent and the celebratory tea poured, now feels like a good time to pause and reflect.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
