<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Elise Cutts</title>
        <link>https://elisecutts.com/</link>
        <description>Elise Cutts&#39; Personal Wesbite</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>me@elisecutts.com (Elise Cutts)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>me@elisecutts.com (Elise Cutts)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 21:37:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://elisecutts.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>The Origin of Life Debate Has Never Been Civil</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/the-origin-of-life-debate-has-never-been-civil/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 21:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://elisecutts.com/the-origin-of-life-debate-has-never-been-civil/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The public origin of life debate sometimes feels like a parallel universe to the scientific one. And in many ways, it really is a parallel debate.—the big questions have almost nothing to do with one antoher and, more fundamentally, the battle raging beyond the ivory tower has more to do with faith than research. According to a 2019 Gallup poll, 40% of Americans believe that God created humans in their current form no more than about 10,000 years ago. And if that&rsquo;s your view, it doesn&rsquo;t much matter whether the person you&rsquo;re debating thinks that life got started at a hydrothermal vent on the bottom of the ocean or in a warm little pond of primordial soup. That&rsquo;s just not the point.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Is there a truly light-independent ecosystem?</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/is-there-a-truly-light-independent-ecosystem/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 08:22:09 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://elisecutts.com/is-there-a-truly-light-independent-ecosystem/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Oxygen is one of those things that nobody thinks about unless they either don&rsquo;t have it or they&rsquo;re a scientist. Either way, once you <em>do</em> start to think about oxygen, its usually not long until you start thinking there&rsquo;s nothing more important in the universe.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>1000-word German flashcard deck</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/2020-10-11-1000-word-german-flashcard-deck/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 21:06:18 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://elisecutts.com/2020-10-11-1000-word-german-flashcard-deck/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="details admonition info open">
        <div class="details-summary admonition-title">
            <i class="icon fas fa-info-circle fa-fw"></i>Update: improved card format available<i class="details-icon fas fa-angle-right fa-fw"></i>
        </div>
        <div class="details-content">
            <div class="admonition-content"><p>I&rsquo;ve kept working on my Anki card format and now have a much better template than the one I use in this deck.</p>
<p>My new template <u><strong>automatically generates cloze deletions based on example sentences</strong></u> (no need to make separate notes for clozes or make &ldquo;fake&rdquo; clozes on basic cards by hand) and <u><strong>color-codes nouns by gender</strong></u> using conditional formatting.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/anki-format-for-german-that-automatically-generates-cloze-deletions-and-color-codes-nouns/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Check out the template</a>, or read my post about <a href="https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">conditional formatting in Anki based on field contents</a>.</p>
<p>You can find those posts on <a href="www.monoglotanxiety.com" rel="">my language blog, Monoglot Anxiety</a>. I decided it was best to separate my language hobby from my personal homepage, so all future German/Anki posts will be there.</p>
</div>
        </div>
    </div>
<p>After finishing Duolingo German, I started making digital flashcards so that I&rsquo;d have something to keep my iThumbs occupied through corona lockdown better than scrolling through the reams of international and domestic horrors served up by my newsfeed. I ended up spending months of experimenting with Anki and looking into popular German vocabulary sets online, and <a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1877324510" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">this 1000-word flashcard deck of core German vocabulary</a>  is the result.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>I, extremophile</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/2020-09-16-i-extremophile/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://elisecutts.com/2020-09-16-i-extremophile/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Something I&rsquo;ve thoroughly enjoyed in the first few weeks of taking a phylogenomics course is getting to think about non-microbial life for a change. The class will reorient its focus in a microbial direction here in the upcoming weeks, but thinking about familiar groups of macroscopic organisms to start makes it a lot easier to get a grip on fundamental concepts in phylogenomics and evolution.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Safe and sound and COVID-19 negative back in the US</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/2020-09-01-safe-and-sound-and-covid-19-negative/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://elisecutts.com/2020-09-01-safe-and-sound-and-covid-19-negative/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Coming to Boston was definitely easier than going to Denmark this summer—at least there wasn&rsquo;t a risk of being turned away at the border—but it also wasn&rsquo;t exactly <em>easy</em>. Cancelled flights, state travel rules, booked-up COVID-19 test centers, and layer upon layer of MIT pandemic policy made it all a bit more complicated than I anticipated.</p>
<p>And on top of all that, my mattress won&rsquo;t be here for another week! They said 3-5 days 14 days ago!</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Review: MITx 6001.x Introduction to Computer Science and Programming using Python</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/2020-08-19-review-mitx-6001-x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://elisecutts.com/2020-08-19-review-mitx-6001-x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m going to go out on a limb here and guess that most scientists didn&rsquo;t decide to become reseachers because they dreamed of pouring hours into Matlab scripts and peering at liness of code on a computer screen.</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
