<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Elise Cutts</title>
    <link>https://elisecutts.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Elise Cutts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Elise Cutts</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elisecutts.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some of my newbie science writing mistakes</title>
      <link>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-10-21-newbie-science-writer-edits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-10-21-newbie-science-writer-edits/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit over three months now since I started writing
1. Forgetting to consider conflicts of interest     The single most important decision I made related to science writing was joining NASW. For students, it&amp;rsquo;s only $20 to join and the value is fantastic. NASW offers networking opportunities, hosts an annual conference for science writers, and has lots of resources, fellowships, and other support for science writers at every stage of their careers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got my first science journalism clip</title>
      <link>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-07-17-my-path-to-a-first-science-news-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-07-17-my-path-to-a-first-science-news-story/</guid>
      <description>I suspect that there are plenty of other researchers out there who are at least toying with the idea that writing about science might be more fun than actually doing it. But how to start?
Breaking into science writing without media experience is intimidating, but it is possible. My first reported science story ran this week in Science News, and seeing as the obligatory rounds of self-promotional texts have been sent and the celebratory tea poured, now feels like a good time to pause and reflect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of life debate has never been civil</title>
      <link>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-01-14-origins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2021-01-14-origins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Engraving of Félix Archimède Pouchet, a rival of Louis Pasteur&amp;rsquo;s in the origin of life debate&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public origin of life debate sometimes feels like a parallel universe to the scientific one. And in many ways, it really is a parallel debate.—the big questions have almost nothing to do with one antoher and, more fundamentally, the battle raging beyond the ivory tower has more to do with faith than research. According to a 2019 Gallup poll, 40% of Americans believe that God created humans in their current form no more than about 10,000 years ago. And if that&amp;rsquo;s your view, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t much matter whether the person you&amp;rsquo;re debating thinks that life got started at a hydrothermal vent on the bottom of the ocean or in a warm little pond of primordial soup. That&amp;rsquo;s just not the point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a truly light-independent ecosystem?</title>
      <link>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2020-12-19-oxygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisecutts.com/blog/2020-12-19-oxygen/</guid>
      <description>Oxygen is one of those things that nobody thinks about unless they either don&amp;rsquo;t have it or they&amp;rsquo;re a scientist. Either way, once you do start to think about oxygen, its usually not long until you start thinking there&amp;rsquo;s nothing more important in the universe.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about oxygen lately, and not because I&amp;rsquo;m suffocating. And naturally, I have become something of an oxygen conspiracy theorist. It&amp;rsquo;s everywhere!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
